ABHIJIT BAISHYA



ABOUT MF

Advanced web designer/developer with ten years of experience in designing and developing interactive websites, web application and mobile apps. A versatile web professional with ability to multitask on various projects while maintaining schedule, delivering creative solutions under aggregative deadlines and bearing communicative efficiencies.

WORKING EXPERIENCES

#	Designation	Organization	Duration
1.	FullStack Engineer	Beamplus	April 23 to till now
2.	Programmer	Tezpur University	2015 - 2023
3.	Junior programmer	Tezpur University	2013 - 2015

Below are the list of projects I have completed recently.

Smart Contract Scanning (Securat, Hong kong)

April 2023 to till now

- Designed and developed a web application using React and python.
- Created custom components with React and styled them with Tailwind CSS.
- Developed RESTful APIs and integrated them with Firebase.
- Implemented user authentication and authorization using Firebase Authentication.
- Collaborated with the QA team to identify and fix bugs in the application.
- Participated in code reviews and provided feedback to team members to improve code quality.

Mobile App for Chiropractor (India)

July 2022 to March 2023

- Developed and maintained mobile applications using React Native for iOS and Android platforms.
- Developed and implemented features such as user authentication, push notifications, and location-based services.
- Created responsive and user-friendly interfaces with React Native and React.js.
- Implemented state management using Redux.
- Worked with RESTful APIs and GraphQL to fetch and manage data from backend systems.
- Implemented local data storage using SQLite and cloud-based storage using Firebase.
- Worked with cross-functional teams to identify business requirements and develop technical solutions that met their needs.
- . Booking and management system.



EDUCATION

MCA Tezpur University Assam India

SKILLS

HTML5 CSS3

JavaScript

JQuery

Php Mysql

Ajax

ISON

Node

React

React Native

GraphQL

Python

Restful APIs

SOL

Firebase

MongoDB

Mongoose Library

CONTACT

+91 7576876122

abhijit@securat.in, abhijitbaishya69@gmail. com

Online Recruitment System (Tezpur University, Assam, India)

December 2021 to May 2022

- Developed and maintained web applications using modern front-end and back-end technologies such as React, Node.js, and MongoDB.
- Created responsive and user-friendly interfaces with HTML, CSS and JavaScript frameworks.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to identify business requirements and develop technical solutions that met their needs.
- Designed and implemented RESTful APIs using Node.js and Flask to communicate between the front-end and back-end.
- · Implemented database schema designs and optimized database performance.
- · Worked with Azure to deploy and manage applications in a cloud environment.
- . Designed application Docker and deployed in University Server.
- Participated in code reviews and collaborated with team members to improve code quality and maintainability.

Character Antecedent Verification system (State Police, Assam, India)

May 2020 to September 2021

- Developed and maintained web applications using PHP and Laravel framework.
- Implemented payment Razorpay payment gateways for transactions.
- · Designed and implemented database schemas using MySQL.
- · Worked with RESTful APIs to fetch and manage data from backend systems.
- Worked with cross-functional teams to identify business requirements and develop technical solutions that met their needs.
- · Participated in code reviews and provided feedback to team members to improve code quality.

Other Projects

Online Admission System (Tezpur University)
Learning Management System (BN College, Assam, India)
Online Repository System (UNICEF India)
Internal Complaint Committee (Tezpur University)